Jason Engle

12190 Winding Oak Trl Alpharetta, GA 30005

404-446-5466

jasonericengle@yahoo.com

PMP certified professional skilled in all phases of a project life cycle, from initial feasibility analysis and conceptual design through implementation and enhancement. Effective at building globally diverse, delivery-focused teams. Excellent business process and strategic skills; specializing in delivery of Oracle Applications and related technology solutions.

Additional Strengths Include:

- Result Driven & Customer Focused
- Business Intelligence Solutions
- Strategic Planning and Transformation
- Technology Architecture and Integration
- Governance and Standards Definition
- IT Talent Management
- Business Process Automation
- Front and Back-Office System Management

Work Experience

VERINT SYSTEMS, Alpharetta, GA Senior Director, Technical Services (2012-Present)

Oversee the global development and reporting teams for a billion-dollar high tech company with over 5,000 employees throughout the world. Supervise 15 global direct reports plus additional onsite and offshore contracted personnel. Work closely with the applications teams to deliver software solutions that transform the business to drive revenue and reduce operational cost.

- ➤ Developed the corporate business intelligence strategy, emphasizing business self-service reporting capabilities through the use of Tableau and MS Power BI visual analytics, supported by a comprehensive underlying data layer. Consolidated several legacy reporting applications and enabled the business to identify several key opportunities to generate revenue and minimize operational costs.
- Led the transformation of the global consolidation and financial processes through the roll-out of Hyperion's latest cloud application suite, including Hyperion Financial Management (HFM) and Smart View. Project team included internal and external vendor staff, with high level visibility to the executive steering committees and global finance leadership.
- Reengineered the processes and governance model surrounding the intake, development and delivery of technical solutions. Created documentation to clearly define development standards and implemented the Stat for Oracle E-Business Suite change management solution to enforce process and securely migrate objects throughout the software development lifecycle.

DELOITTE CONSULTING, Charlotte, NC Senior Manager (2006-2012)

Client service professional of a leading global consulting firm. As the manager of multi-million dollar engagements, worked closely with client leadership through the sales and project phases. Responsible for delivery, financials management (including invoice processing and budget adherence), and issue escalation and resolution. Supervised large project teams made up of onsite and offshore resources.

Jason Engle

12190 Winding Oak Trl Alpharetta, GA 30005

404-446-5466

jasonericengle@yahoo.com

- ➤ Project manager for an Oracle enterprise resource planning (ERP) implementation, replacing legacy systems and processes through business transformation. All Financial, Supply Chain, and Human Resources processes were in scope. Overall responsibility for budget, timeline and delivery. Successful implementation and strong client relationships led to several years of continued partnership and additional client service opportunities.
- Leader of the Master Data Management (MDM) and Enterprise Application Integration (EAI) streams of a global business case evaluation for one of the world's largest pharmaceutical companies. The team focused on the benefits, both in data integrity (improved analytics, one 'source of truth') and cost savings (through systems and resource consolidation), achieved by enforcing policies, governance procedures, and overall system integration capabilities to the corporate bottom-line. Multi-million dollar savings were identified.
- ➤ Technical manager for several full ERP implementations with up to 100+ custom enhancements. Responsibilities included (but were not limited to) documenting the as-is and future-state application landscape (including roadmap), development of the technical development standards for Oracle RICE objects, governance surrounding all technical components, resource loading, and coordination with functional teams. Projects utilized the Oracle Fusion Middleware family of tools and service orientated architecture (SOA) strategies.

Additional Employment History

Senior Consultant, Titan Technology Partners
Project Manager, Invacare Corporation
Independent Consultant
Senior Consultant, Whittman-Hart
Senior Systems Project Leader, Baker Furniture
Technical Consultant, Oracle Corporation
December 2006 – February 2006
June 2001 – April 2002
June 1999 – June 2001
July 1997 – June 1999
June 1995 – July 1997

Education and Certifications

- Bachelors of Science; Grand Valley State University, Allendale, MI 1995
- Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification; 2011

Technical Skills

- Oracle Applications 10.6 12.2.5
- Oracle Development Suite (Forms/Reports/WF/SQLLDR)
- Oracle SOA (BPEL, OSB)
- Stat for Oracle E-Business Suite
- Tableau, MS Power BI
- SQL, PLSQL, Unix Technical Languages